ROBERTA MAWUNYO AKOTO

PRODUCT MANAGER

Ghana | +233 541718326 | LinkedIn | akotoro22@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A driven and enthusiastic Junior Product Manager with 3+ years of experience in product development, market research, and project management also have 6+years of experience as a software engineer. Possesses a solid foundation in agile methodologies and user-centred design, and is dedicated to delivering high-quality products that exceed customer expectations. Demonstrates a strong ability to work collaboratively in teams and excellent communication skills and an experience in Education, AgriTech, Content publishing and FinTech.

CORE SKILLS

Project Management, Web design and development, Communication, Team Supervision, Customer Management, Technical Writing, Investing, Agile Methodologies, User-centered Design, Testing and debugging, Documentation, and Software Development Lifecycle.

Tools: Jira, Trello, MixPanel, Confluence, Asana, Figma, Miro, Mural, Docker, Photoshop. **Tech stacks:** SQL (MySQL and MariaDB), JavaScript (Vue. Js, React.js and Vanilla), GraphQL, Apollo and PHP(Laravel and CakePHP).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Manager / Co-founder, AppGharage, Ghana.

May. 2020 - Present

- Drove, and Mentored a team of 4 engineers, planning sprints and performing user research.
- Conducted market research and competitive analysis to identify new product opportunities.
- Developed business plans to evaluate the market opportunity and strategic fit for new product concepts.
- Worked collaboratively with designers and developers to create wireframes and prototypes for new products.
- Worked closely with engineers to successfully build and deploy applications.

Software Engineer, Ampifire, Hong Kong.

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2022

- Developed and Co-led a new feature which increased distribution and customer acquisition by at least 30%.
- Increased content publishing efficiency by integrating an API by 50%.
- Added features to our platform with 5000+ monthly users, enabling image uploads which convert into videos and slideshows.
- Developed and implemented software features using Cake PHP, Docker and vue.is.
- Tested and debugged software code to ensure high-quality code delivery.

Software Engineer, Agrocenta, Ghana.

Jun. 2019 – Jun. 2020

- Built a platform to lend and improve cash flow to over 300 users through responsive customer experience.
- Performed market research on digitising agricultural cereal value chains to let us know the niche market and how we could strategise and break into this agricultural market.
- Built and managed multiple projects simultaneously, including website redesigns, and mobile app development.
- Defined design objectives and system design documents to build mobile-first applications.
- Collaborated with team members to develop project timelines and ensure the timely delivery of features.

Product Manager and Co-founder, Epay, Ghana.

Sep. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- Designed, developed and launched a payment service platform (Stripe but for Africa) which processed payments of over \$200,000 in value for the business within 14 months through payment pages.
- Conducted user testing and gathered feedback to iterate on product designs.
- Developed business plans to evaluate the market opportunity and strategic fit.
- Constantly reviewed customer feedback and usage in order to plan out ways to improve our services which increased performance and usage by 30%.
- Developed and wrote API integration guides and documentation for our technical and non-technical users.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science In Information Technology

Jan. 2016 – Apr. 2019

Knutsford University College, Accra

CERTIFICATIONS

Software Product Management(Coursera), Technical Product Management(LinkedIn), Product Analytics Certification(Product School), Business Management Essentials(MSI)